no drops coppice
that's right guys we have finally done
it
after years almost a year I know bro I
didn't sleep last night I took a nap
today I'm kind of tired after a year of
shipping the same model over and over
again
we are finally shipping a new model 0.4
0.7 begins the release of the latest and
greatest thanks to all of you for
contributing all of your data back to us
we've taken all that data if you have a
gray panda by the way if you have a gray
panda the model is probably going to
work better for you because you were
involved in the training set I think we
have like we have like 80 of our users
who've contributed if you don't have
great panda I shot that commented AI get
a great pant in the day and you'll be
included in the next model training so
you'll get an even better model so
that's the first thing we're here to
talk about the second thing we're here
to talk about is we have shipped our
official GM volt support thank you thank
you all to V tasarov you know the
claimer of the GM bounty
he's done a great job getting that code
to us we paid out the $10,000 bounty to
him we've cleaned it up he actually lent
us the car for a week and now we have
pushed that upstream you guys saw the
periscope vault support is top-notch
it's really it's really one of the best
supported cars right now
GM's actuators are pretty nice we have
also shipped thanks to energy GM Bosch
lateral support
I should really include the thanks will
include the thanks in that in the
release is all edit it um so so our
energy got a two thousand dollar bounty
for Honda Bosch lateral support which
has now been up streamed as well thanks
to energy for that we've improved
actuator modeling to reduce lateral
wobble we're now taking into account if
there's a delay that's the large cause
of wobble it's not caused by models it's
caused by lag in the whole loop the Volt
has both lateral and longitudinal
absolutely we've also shipped support
for the lateral only Cadillac ct-6 so in
case anybody has that car our CD six is
super nice we have a button now you
could switch between open pilot and
super cruise um so if you want super
Cruiser press super cruise button if you
want to open pilot just put on the
adaptive cruise and you get off the path
so it's a nice is us a nice of sikhi six
anywhere it's a great car if I was less
tired I'd take you guys out for a ride
but I am kind of tired this is a good
release zero point four point seven we
refactored the car abstraction layer so
we aren't gonna be ops trimming any more
cars um maybe if somebody hands us know
so we can talk about why no Volvo in a
minute a 20-18 camera yes absolutely yes
Honda's Toyota's and GM's will be up
stripped
we're not up streaming anymore brands
because we don't want to maintain
there's some chance if people do like a
Hyundai port or a Nissan port we'd
consider it but things like the Tesla
port unfortunately
it's it's it's too much effort for us to
for us to maintain all these all these
cars um so that's it if you top Honda
Toyota GM we were gonna do Ford Ford is
over we're never doing subaru no Subaru
absolutely not but uh Tesla bounty what
I've said about that is
you know they worked hard on a great job
to to collude and Zacks
one-two-three-four the test report if
you guys saw the electric article they
got some great press about that good for
them great press for us too
so you know big big big props to them
for doing that and we will if they
manage to get ten people using the port
we will pay them the bounty even though
unfortunately we won't be up streaming
yet we've talked about this on slack so
we factor the car abstraction layer that
we refactor the car abstraction layer to
make the cars as much like plugins as
possible so other people can maintain oh
yeah we're really not gonna be up
streaming anything else but ideally we
want community maintainer x' of these
other cars and what we will try to do
our commitment to you guys is we'll try
to make open pilot as modular as
possible have the api's change as little
as possible
so if you write a carport it should be
relatively easy to know bring it through
to the new versions and hack around or
be startup issue
I shouldn't even included that that's
kind of gross I just sort of descriptor
like tries it a bunch of times
Starro terrible cop bad cop and I should
feel bad but yeah so let's take a look
so here zero point four point seven
these are the things I promised new
model that's of course envision D vault
lateral vault lateral and longitudinal
ct-6 lateral Honda Bosch lateral so
that's the Accord
that's the gets the chain flog in a
minute that's the cord that's the CRV
and that's the Civic hatchback those
should all three of those cars should be
supported and we will be shipping a
Bosch giraffe next week probably okay so
see we got here what up no yes so you
can look through into the changes here
the resource is we've got a little stuff
oh if we've merged in the Tesla
little-endian support thank you for that
we've also shipped our half Ford port so
there's a there's a four port here
there's no car control or fellowship
that too but there's no official support
for the Ford Civic yep yeah all the
civics without supporting yeah have fun
with the ten seconds for Jeff Ford's are
a real disappointment ship that but we
shifted the GM port work in the volt and
the Cadillac port into one a couple
changes to Honda change the Toyota minor
changes all throughout the thing and of
course the new model binary file not
shown envision D as will enjoy it
bull endian foot so it works with Cabana
yeah yeah if you say if you say - did
you see the Cabana was a little Indian
open pilot should now respect that so
respect we got Le'Veon that's it that's
really what we want to talk about we did
the release we dropped it is live let's
go for a drive Wow
I think as I we got a life let's go
oh yeah got that key bro mount for you
guys no not really no all right I will
take a job we'll take a drive pretty bad
boy shoes on here got my shoes a rav4
good now I haven't tried it I don't know
it might be a little bit worse but
hopefully it'll be kind of okay alright
let's go people working on the weekends
left with my people working on the
weekends ain't turn off Wi-Fi turn off
Wi-Fi I don't know this just isn't gonna
work well oh well yeah so here we are in
our ct6 I'm just gonna reboot it make
sure I got the latest stuff just make
sure I got the latest stuff on here
check the version 0.4 0.7 right there I
don't think we broke support for the
pedal but you guys know the pedals not
officially supported so 104.7 here let's
go for a drive
so we can look at UI oh my god I can't
see door neighbor's hate us having so
many cars now cuz they're not usually
here
don't cast this you have to give it
above a certain speed I never go right
yeah go up and pilot
and what up guys so we're just driving
through the neighborhood with
neighborhood pilot seeing those lanes
pretty well oh this is so good the new
model is really good guys it's great
victory
remember keep your eyes on the road at
all times
every self-driving car in the world
today is the level - whoa who is this
gonna work
so actually that's not even a hit on
Oakland pilot that's the GM longitudinal
so the Cadillac is actually only lateral
an Oakland pilot we're using GM's
longitudinal control
nope new model guys not gonna get fired
nope nope nope
we're fans of new model the new model
was early we have ground truthing guy
ground truthing guy got a promotion the
head of mapping and localization got a
promotion he's now a VP for doing a
great job with the ground truthing of
this model I'm an ml guy came through
and trained a model alright on here
but yeah so we're actually using GM's
adaptive cruise here a new model is
released now yeah yeah so there should
be a new model every release all of this
stuff is finally back I've been working
with beautiful infrastructure we hired a
great infrastructure guy well close with
that following there's a button for
following that here we go oh yeah
someone set it to near I like far on my
gap you know mean old man
um but yeah so this is open pilot 0.4
0.7 with the newest greatest model when
you're on my way mistakes are down yeah
you love that fan sound bro I know the
last model is sold at new walls pretty
sick though yep I got a press resume
because open pile is not doing that
actually even the vault you have to
press resume it kind of sucks I don't
think we shipped resume spamming but
yeah look at that quality oh love this
model guys it feels so good no new
calibration hasn't shipped yet that's
coming probably in the next release um
that guys on vacation for a week now so
you know but ya know the new model is
sick
it feels like I'm dead in the center of
the road right now
but this supercruise quality guys this
is a really super creased quality no
traffic lights no no no no no updating
zero point four point seven let me know
how it works we think that this model is
similar you know Tesla came out with
their new model and people were big fans
all the talk our problem well darling if
you have a tall car you might be a
little disappointed I don't like the
problem with open pilot being a lateral
only it's like I'm seeing a blue fuse
here lit fuse infused okay on the realm
of the open pilot being lateral only is
we can't show we don't show the radar
point
RDX yeah RDX worse
oh yeah look at that driving across that
intersection and keep me in the lane so
quality is that Eon new no this is one
of our yawns what's wrong with taller
cars we don't know just a bug
I don't know they might agree or it
might work look internally is a team I
don't really know what the latest on
tall cars but ya know it's pretty sick
if you have a civic really gonna work
well or a Korg I hear great things on
the team driving the hacker would zero
point four point seven get it down
worried right now github.com slash
calming I slash open pilot you've got a
civic you're gonna love it
still thinking about camera yeah a
hacker Dan a cord will do that yeah I
was thinking about the cavalry I think
we gotta trade the ILX in for Camry but
there's a contingent in the company that
doesn't think we should trade in the ILX
because it has sentimental value what do
you guys think
open pilot 0.4 0.7 new model it's sick
if you don't have an eon we got plenty
of food for sale shop combinati i don't
get a sugru you're gonna regret it
you're gonna be like why did I get a
Subaru I already know how you're gonna
feel right so this is a tricky part
let's see what the new model does here
let's see if we can do this
whoa whoa little out of there but that
felt pretty good guys that was all open
pilots you saw that crazy all those
crazy lanes didn't matter I'm just gonna
op my speed here send me back speed to
70 let's go we'll switch over to super
cruise at some point in this drive too
so we can really compare the tip but
this is open pilot the over your lesbian
friends have a super you can't upgrade
your 64 4:128 we don't know for that
yeah that was nuts that just worked do a
little sick bro this feels this feels
amazing
what powers Drive you know look at look
at those solid legs look another right
on the things this is as good as super
crystal
one of the reasons okay so this tourism
supercruise appears better than over
pilot one is that it only works on this
car and this car has particularly good
actuators
not a link cut in here the other reason
is that supercruise only allows you to
engage in very conservative areas so
like even that Lane merge might have
been a disengagement for supercruise
direct sunlight can't drive I don't know
maps will probably help a bit
I've got some real turn up ahead oh yeah
I get it open pile I get it
this is this is the best release yet I'm
so happy
all right so let's see when supercruise
becomes available this has been open
pilot driving we're going to switch over
to super cruise in a minute so you can
see that there's no super cruise yet on
the dashboard cut in here we switch over
to super cruise super cruise blinked on
for a second this turn is beyond what
super cruise can do actually so this is
still open pilot but this feels as good
as super cruise guess I can not I can't
even tell about it so confused to be
honest
this is unreal
yes gotta love this
thank you for sticking with us in the
year it took us to produce a new model I
know we're terrible
so what we're gonna do in a second when
that supercruise logo appears we're
gonna disengage open pilot with a switch
over to super first we're gonna see if
we can feel the difference
hahaha no wobbling Oh unbelievable
now you know your mobile data it's
recommended but you don't
where's the supercruise logo
listen Bogg do we break supercruise in
this car
up there yep it blinked on for half a
second why come on super cruise on super
cruise she's super cruise logo appears
right there guys I can't even tell him
not here we go okay let's get on super
cruise disengage all pilots I'm driving
now let's see if super Christmas show
chosen for half a second no no we might
have broken something
all right now supercruise is on
so this is GM's this is GM's driving
system you see those infrared lights
turn on
it feels almost the same
as super Chris feels a little bit
tighter I don't know or maybe it just
feels more convincing and a green turned
on and stuff like it looks like it's
doing something major EPS firmware
difference is not that major enough that
we can check own you do have to command
them a bit differently but why the
Cadillac has all this extra redundant
safety stuff but yeah so this is
supercruise it does feel a little better
it's hard to describe it's not exactly
clear what's different about supercruise
versus open pilot but this feels a
little better it's subtle it's very
subtle I'm hoping by the time by the
time the end of the year comes around we
will be we will be better than
supercruise we will meet this promise no
problem
it feels smoother yeah oh supercruise
feel smoother no it's very hard to say
I'm gonna disengage supercruise in a
minute we'll go back to open pilot and
we'll see what the difference we'll see
if I can still
alright we're on here
this turn feels good I'll switch back to
open pilot
yes it cruises off such an act open
pilots
yeah it doesn't feel as confidence
it's a little it wobbles a little more
around the turn it turns a little later
into the Turk do you feel like you're on
a rail with supercruise we're with open
pilot you feel like you're it's like a
kid just learning to drive is there a
new chime yeah yeah so that time is
being set over GM loud and realize it
worked in the catalog that's actually
being bit bang GM lamb which is crazy
what steering button so I'm just using
the supercruise button to engage
superfruits and I'm using the adaptive
cruise control button to add a chapter
cruise control
I mean really what we have to do is
here's what we're gonna do I'm gonna get
in the passenger seat and we'll put a
put a divider up between me and the
driver and we'll play the open pilot or
supercruise game and then we can we can
advertise in a double blind taste test
open pilot compares favorably to
supercruise but okay it's weird I don't
understand why it's not showing up like
I'm not really sure how that detection
works hopefully we can hack supercruise
to appear everywhere I Cho we can really
get ahead - honestly guys I can't tell
him about servers right now it feels the
same
at least on that turn so there's a
little bit of a sharper turn coming up I
think supercruise is a little better
when the turns get a little sharper
there is a very subtle amount of wobble
still present on it
no it can also just be my perception
like I know it's an open pilot I know
it's in super loose
I've also seen open violent make
mistakes I've ever really seen
supercruise make mistakes all right so
let's let's just engage a pilot
let's so let's give the supercruise logo
a second to show up
we're back on supercruise
it feels better it feels better um so
we're gonna I'm gonna take this drive
back we're gonna look at the cabana tres
and yeah it's confidence it feels it
feels more confident we'll look at the
Cabana trace and we'll see what the
actual commands to the actuator how they
differ
I'm so happy you bought this car too
this is this is one of our best
purchases so I could really I love that
I have both right now I can switch
between them with the press of a button
cool
all right guys yeah again blinded by
that's doing real light thank you for
joining this periscope that is today's
comparison between okapi live and super
cruise